America: Imagine the World Without Her is a
documentary film directed by Dinesh D'Souza.
A story that questions the shaming of the US through revisionist history, lies and omissions by educational institutions,
political organizations, Alinsky, Barack Obama, Hillary Clinton, and other progressives to destroy America.
Self, played by Dinesh D'Souza.
Self - US President (archive footage), played by Barack Obama.
Frederick Douglass, played by Josh Bonzie.
Saul Alinsky, played by Rich Bentz.
Crew Member, played by Grady Allen Bishop.
Young George Washington, played by John Koopman.
America: Imagine the World Without Her is a 2014 American right-wing conspiracy propaganda
film by political commentator Dinesh D'Souza based on his book of the same name.
It is a follow-up to his film 2016: Obama's America (2012).
In the film, D'Souza contends that parts of United States history are improperly and negatively
highlighted by liberals, which he seeks to counter with positive highlights.
Topics addressed include conquest of Indigenous and Mexican lands,
slavery, and matters relating to foreign policy and capitalism.
D'Souza collaborated with John Sullivan and Bruce Schooley to
adapt his book of the same name into a screenplay.
D'Souza produced the film with Gerald R.
Molen and directed it with Sullivan.
The film combined historical reenactments with
interviews with different political figures.
America: Imagine the World Without Her was marketed to political
conservatives and through Christian marketing firms.
Lionsgate released the film in three theaters on June 27, 2014 and
expanded its distribution on the weekend of the U.S.
holiday Independence Day on July 4, 2014.
The film grossed $14.4 million, which made it the highest-grossing documentary in the United States in 2014,
though D'Souza's previous documentary 2016: Obama's America had grossed over $33 million.
Most professional film critics called the film poorly-made and partisan.
Political commentators analyzed D'Souza's rebuttal of Howard Zinn's criticisms, the filmmaker's treatment of Saul
Alinsky, Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton, and D'Souza's depiction of his own criminal prosecution.
Conservative commentators expressed a mix of full and qualified
support for the documentary and D'Souza's intentions.